        <section xml:id="ch027_storage-idpH123">
            <title>SWAuth</title>
            <para>SWAuth is another popular alternative to Keystone.
            In contrast to Keystone it stores the user accounts,
            credentials, and metadata in object storage itself.  More
            specifics about where the objects are stored can be found
            on the SWAuth website at
            <link xlink:href="http://gholt.github.io/swauth/">http://gholt.github.io/swauth/</link>.</para>
            <para>SWAuth has these types of roles (or groups) for a
            user:</para>
            <informaltable>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>.super_admin</td>
                        <td>Can perform any action on any
                        OpenStack Account, Container, or Object</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>.reseller_admin</td>
                        <td>Can perform most actions on
                        any OpenStack Account, Container, or Object.
                        Cannot create other reseller admins.
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>.admin</td>
                        <td>Can perform actions limited to
                        the single OpenStack Account it belongs to</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Regular User</td>
                        <td>Can access containers or
                        objects they have permission to in the
                        OpenStack Account to which they belong
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </informaltable>
            <para>The following table provides a matrix of what each
            role/group can do:</para>
            <figure>
                <title>Object storage SWAuth role matrix</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject role="html">
                        <imagedata contentdepth="393"
                            contentwidth="1047"
                            fileref="static/swift_swauth_roles_matrix.png"
                            format="PNG" scalefit="1"/>
                    </imageobject>
                    <imageobject role="fo">
                        <imagedata contentdepth="100%"
                            fileref="static/swift_swauth_roles_matrix.png"
                            format="PNG" scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <warning><para>The super admin key is stored in
            <filename>/etc/swift/proxy-server.conf</filename> and MUST
            be protected!  See the File Permissions section for
            guidance on protecting this file.  Frequent changing of
            this key is recommended.</para></warning>
            <para>One approach for administration is to create an
            OpenStack Object Storage Account called "CloudAdmins" and
            create reseller_admin users in that account.  Each user
            will be able to do administrative functions in all the
            other accounts.  Creating a reseller_admin will require
            the super admin key.</para>
            <para>Another useful way to secure the super admin key is
            to have it exist only on the proxy server and retrieve the
            key on-demand via ssh or by running the command on the
            proxy server itself and using a grep to extract the key on
            the fly.</para>
            <section xml:id="ch027_storage-idpH1234">
                <title>Protecting cloud administration</title>
                <para>When using SWAuth you can actually designate
                that certain proxy service nodes are to NOT allow
                administrator API calls.  This is useful if you have
                Proxy service nodes on the public Internet and wish to
                restrict administration functions to only special
                Proxy service nodes on a private network.  This is
                done by setting the
                <code>allow_account_managment</code> to false in your
                <filename>proxy-server.conf</filename>.</para>
                <para>Another important consideration is that the
                SWAuth command line tools expose the user credentials
                on the command-line.  The system from which they are
                executed must be secure to prevent disclosure in the
                process list to other uses.  Another option is to use
                the SWAuth admin REST API to implement your own admin
                CLI tools that don’t expose the key as a command-line
                option.</para>
            </section>
            <section xml:id="ch027_storage-idpH12345">
                <title>Salting and hashing passwords</title>
                <para>SWAuth by default stores passwords in
                clear-text.  It also offers a sha1 hashing provider,
                but the salt used is global.  Additionally, no
                iterations or key stretching is performed.  This is a
                limitation of SWAuth.</para>
                <para>You may optionally add-in your own hashing code
                or provider as a hook to SWAuth.  See the
                <link xlink:href="http://gholt.github.io/swauth/dev/authtypes.html">SWAuth code and site</link>
                for details.</para>
                <para>If you use the global salt be sure to secure it
                and back it up.  If you have multiple proxy nodes each
                one has to have a copy so that may be good enough for
                you.  If you ever lose it or change it then all
                existing user passwords will not work and will have to
                be reset.</para>
                <para>You should make sure the salt you choose is
                generated using a cryptographically secure random
                number generator and of sufficient length.  At least
                20 characters is recommended.</para>
                <para>The salt is stored in the
                <filename>/etc/swift/proxy-server.conf</filename>
                file which must be secured with proper ACLs.  See the
                File Permissions section for guidance.</para>
            </section>
        </section><!-- SWAuth -->
    </section><!-- Object Storage Authentication -->